{
  "meta": {
    "disclaimer": "Do not rely on openFDA to make decisions regarding medical care. While we make every effort to ensure that data is accurate, you should assume all results are unvalidated. We may limit or otherwise restrict your access to the API in line with our Terms of Service.",
    "terms": "https://open.fda.gov/terms/",
    "license": "https://open.fda.gov/license/",
    "last_updated": "2019-12-14",
    "results": {
      "skip": 0,
      "limit": 1,
      "total": 3
    }
  },
  "results": [
    {
      "effective_time": "20100713",
      "contraindications": [
        "4 CONTRAINDICATIONS 4.1 Hypersensitivity STRATTERA is contraindicated in patients known to be hypersensitive to atomoxetine or other constituents of the product [see Warnings and Precautions (5.7)]. 4.2 Monoamine Oxidase Inhibitors (MAOI) STRATTERA should not be taken with an MAOI, or within 2 weeks after discontinuing an MAOI. Treatment with an MAOI should not be initiated within 2 weeks after discontinuing STRATTERA. With other drugs that affect brain monoamine concentrations, there have been reports of serious, sometimes fatal reactions (including hyperthermia, rigidity, myoclonus, autonomic instability with possible rapid fluctuations of vital signs, and mental status changes that include extreme agitation progressing to delirium and coma) when taken in combination with an MAOI. Some cases presented with features resembling neuroleptic malignant syndrome. Such reactions may occur when these drugs are given concurrently or in close proximity [see Drug Interactions (7.1)]. 4.3 Narrow Angle Glaucoma In clinical trials, STRATTERA use was associated with an increased risk of mydriasis and therefore its use is not recommended in patients with narrow angle glaucoma. Hypersensitivity to atomoxetine or other constituents of product. (4.1) STRATTERA use within 2 weeks after discontinuing MAOI or other drugs that affect brain monoamine concentrations. (4.2, 7.1) Narrow Angle Glaucoma. (4.3"
      ],
      "description": [
        "STRATTERA® (atomoxetine HCl) is a selective norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor. Atomoxetine HCl is the R(-) isomer as determined by x-ray diffraction. The chemical designation is (-)-N-Methyl-3-phenyl-3-(o-tolyloxy)-propylamine hydrochloride. The molecular formula is C17H21NO•HCl, which corresponds to a molecular weight of 291.82Atomoxetine HCl is a white to practically white solid, which has a solubility of 27.8 mg/mL in water. STRATTERA capsules are intended for oral administration only. Each capsule contains atomoxetine HCl equivalent to 10, 18, 25, 40, 60, 80, or 100 mg of atomoxetine. The capsules also contain pregelatinized starch and dimethicone. The capsule shells contain gelatin, sodium lauryl sulfate, and other inactive ingredients. The capsule shells also contain one or more of the following:"
      ],
      "spl_product_data_elements": [
        "Strattera Atomoxetine ATOMOXETINE HYDROCHLORIDE ATOMOXETINE STARCH, CORN DIMETHICONE GELATIN SODIUM LAURYL SULFATE Opaque white LILLY;3228;25;mg Opaque blue"
      ],
      "boxed_warning": [
        "WARNING: SUICIDAL IDEATION IN CHILDREN AND ADOLESCENTS STRATTERA (atomoxetine) increased the risk of suicidal ideation in short-term studies in children or adolescents with Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD). Anyone considering the use of STRATTERA in a child or adolescent must balance this risk with the clinical need. Co-morbidities occurring with ADHD may be associated with an increase in the risk of suicidal ideation and/or behavior. Patients who are started on therapy should be monitored closely for suicidality (suicidal thinking and behavior), clinical worsening, or unusual changes in behavior. Families and caregivers should be advised of the need for close observation and communication with the prescriber. STRATTERA is approved for ADHD in pediatric and adult patients. STRATTERA is not approved for major depressive disorder. Pooled analyses of short-term (6 to 18 weeks) placebo-controlled trials of STRATTERA in children and adolescents (a total of 12 trials involving over 2200 patients, including 11 trials in ADHD and 1 trial in enuresis) have revealed a greater risk of suicidal ideation early during treatment in those receiving STRATTERA compared to placebo. The average risk of suicidal ideation in patients receiving STRATTERA was 0.4% (5/1357 patients), compared to none in placebo-treated patients (851 patients). No suicides occurred in these trials [see Warnings and Precautions (5.1)]."
      ],
      "openfda": {
        "product_ndc": [
          "49999-636"
        ],
        "nui": [
          "N0000000102",
          "N0000175695"
        ],
        "package_ndc": [
          "49999-636-30"
        ],
        "generic_name": [
          "ATOMOXETINE"
        ],
        "spl_set_id": [
          "0121363e-dcd9-4c24-940b-ea890ab762e7"
        ],
        "brand_name": [
          "Strattera"
        ],
        "original_packager_product_ndc": [
          "0002-3228"
        ],
        "manufacturer_name": [
          "Lake Erie Medical DBA Quality Care Products LLC"
        ],
        "rxcui": [
          "349593",
          "352319"
        ],
        "unii": [
          "ASW034S0B8"
        ],
        "spl_id": [
          "5f48f6d9-92c0-4437-b354-5cbe1ac225cf"
        ],
        "substance_name": [
          "ATOMOXETINE HYDROCHLORIDE"
        ],
        "product_type": [
          "HUMAN PRESCRIPTION DRUG"
        ],
        "route": [
          "ORAL"
        ],
        "pharm_class_moa": [
          "Norepinephrine Uptake Inhibitors [MoA]"
        ],
        "application_number": [
          "NDA021411"
        ],
        "pharm_class_epc": [
          "Norepinephrine Reuptake Inhibitor [EPC]"
        ]
      },
      "version": "2037",
      "dosage_and_administration": [
        "2 DOSAGE AND ADMINISTRATION 2.1 Acute Treatment Dosing of children and adolescents up to 70 kg body weight — STRATTERA should be initiated at a total daily dose of approximately 0.5 mg/kg and increased after a minimum of 3 days to a target total daily dose of approximately 1.2 mg/kg administered either as a single daily dose in the morning or as evenly divided doses in the morning and late afternoon/early evening. No additional benefit has been demonstrated for doses higher than 1.2 mg/kg/day [see Clinical Studies (14)]. The total daily dose in children and adolescents should not exceed 1.4 mg/kg or 100 mg, whichever is less. Dosing of children and adolescents over 70 kg body weight and adults — STRATTERA should be initiated at a total daily dose of 40 mg and increased after a minimum of 3 days to a target total daily dose of approximately 80 mg administered either as a single daily dose in the morning or as evenly divided doses in the morning and late afternoon/early evening. After 2 to 4 additional weeks, the dose may be increased to a maximum of 100 mg in patients who have not achieved an optimal response. There are no data that support increased effectiveness at higher doses [see Clinical Studies (14)]. The maximum recommended total daily dose in children and adolescents over 70 kg and adults is 100 mg. 2.2 Maintenance/Extended Treatment It is generally agreed that pharmacological treatment of ADHD may be needed for extended periods. The benefit of maintaining pediatric patients (ages 6-15 years) with ADHD on STRATTERA after achieving a response in a dose range of 1.2 to 1.8 mg/kg/day was demonstrated in a controlled trial. Patients assigned to STRATTERA in the maintenance phase were generally continued on the same dose used to achieve a response in the open label phase. The physician who elects to use STRATTERA for extended periods should periodically reevaluate the long-term usefulness of the drug for the individual patient [see Clinical Studies (14.1)]. 2.3 General Dosing Information STRATTERA may be taken with or without food. STRATTERA can be discontinued without being tapered. STRATTERA capsules are not intended to be opened, they should be taken whole [see Patient Counseling Information (17.6)]. The safety of single doses over 120 mg and total daily doses above 150 mg have not been systematically evaluated. 2.4 Dosing in Specific Populations Dosing adjustment for hepatically impaired patients — For those ADHD patients who have hepatic insufficiency (HI), dosage adjustment is recommended as follows: For patients with moderate HI (Child-Pugh Class B), initial and target doses should be reduced to 50% of the normal dose (for patients without HI). For patients with severe HI (Child-Pugh Class C), initial dose and target doses should be reduced to 25% of normal [see Use In Specific Populations (8.6)]. Dosing adjustment for use with a strong CYP2D6 inhibitor or in patients who are known to be CYP2D6 PMs — In children and adolescents up to 70 kg body weight administered strong CYP2D6 inhibitors, e.g., paroxetine, fluoxetine, and quinidine, or in patients who are known to be CYP2D6 PMs, STRATTERA should be initiated at 0.5 mg/kg/day and only increased to the usual target dose of 1.2 mg/kg/day if symptoms fail to improve after 4 weeks and the initial dose is well tolerated. In children and adolescents over 70 kg body weight and adults administered strong CYP2D6 inhibitors, e.g., paroxetine, fluoxetine, and quinidine, STRATTERA should be initiated at 40 mg/day and only increased to the usual target dose of 80 mg/day if symptoms fail to improve after 4 weeks and the initial dose is well tolerated."
      ],
      "adverse_reactions": [
        "6 ADVERSE REACTIONS 6.1 Clinical Trials Experience STRATTERA was administered to 5382 children or adolescent patients with ADHD and 1007 adults with ADHD in clinical studies. During the ADHD clinical trials, 1625 children and adolescent patients were treated for longer than 1 year and 2529 children and adolescent patients were treated for over 6 months. Because clinical trials are conducted under widely varying conditions, adverse reaction rates observed in the clinical trials of a drug cannot be directly compared to rates in the clinical trials of another drug and may not reflect the rates observed in practice. Child and Adolescent Clinical Trials Reasons for discontinuation of treatment due to adverse reactions in child and adolescent clinical trials — In acute child and adolescent placebo-controlled trials, 3.0% (48/1613) of atomoxetine subjects and 1.4% (13/945) placebo subjects discontinued for adverse reactions. For all studies, (including open-label and long-term studies), 6.3% of extensive metabolizer (EM) patients and 11.2% of poor metabolizer (PM) patients discontinued because of an adverse reaction. Among STRATTERA-treated patients, irritability (0.3%, N=5); somnolence (0.3%, N=5); aggression (0.2%, N=4); nausea (0.2%, N=4); vomiting (0.2%, N=4); abdominal pain (0.2%, N=4); constipation (0.1%, N=2); fatigue (0.1%, N=2); feeling abnormal (0.1%, N=2); and headache (0.1%, N=2) were the reasons for discontinuation reported by more than 1 patient. Seizures — STRATTERA has not been systematically evaluated in pediatric patients with seizure disorder as these patients were excluded from clinical studies during the product's premarket testing. In the clinical development program, seizures were reported in 0.2% (12/5073) of children whose average age was 10 years (range 6 to 16 years). In these clinical trials, the seizure risk among poor metabolizers was 0.3% (1/293) compared to 0.2% (11/4741) for extensive metabolizers. Commonly observed adverse reactions in acute child and adolescent, placebo-controlled trials — Commonly observed adverse reactions associated with the use of STRATTERA (incidence of 2% or greater) and not observed at an equivalent incidence among placebo-treated patients (STRATTERA incidence greater than placebo) are listed in Table 1. Results were similar in the BID and the QD trial except as shown in Table 2, which shows both BID and QD results for selected adverse reactions based on statistically significant Breslow-Day tests. The most commonly observed adverse reactions in patients treated with STRATTERA (incidence of 5% or greater and at least twice the incidence in placebo patients, for either BID or QD dosing) were: nausea, vomiting, fatigue, decreased appetite, abdominal pain, and somnolence (see Tables 1 and 2). The following adverse reactions occurred in at least 2% of PM patients and were either twice as frequent or statistically significantly more frequent in PM patients compared with EM patients: insomnia (15% of PMs, 10% of EMs); weight decreased (7% of PMs, 4% of EMs); constipation (7% of PMs, 4% of EMs); depression1 (7% of PMs, 4% of EMs); tremor (5% of PMs, 1% of EMs); excoriation (4% of PMs, 2% of EMs); conjunctivitis (3% of PMs, 1% of EMs); syncope (3% of PMs, 1% of EMs); early morning awakening (2% of PMs, 1% of EMs); mydriasis (2% of PMs, 1% of EMs). 1Depression includes the following terms: depression, major depression, depressive symptoms, depressed mood, dysphoria. Adult Clinical Trials Reasons for discontinuation of treatment due to adverse reactions in acute adult placebo-controlled trials — In the acute adult placebo-controlled trials, 11.3% (61/541) atomoxetine subjects and 3.0% (12/405) placebo subjects discontinued for adverse reactions. Among STRATTERA-treated patients, insomnia (0.9%, N=5); nausea (0.9%, N=5); chest pain (0.6%, N=3); fatigue (0.6%, N=3); anxiety (0.4%, N=2); erectile dysfunction (0.4%, N=2); mood swings (0.4%, N=2); nervousness (0.4%, N=2); palpitations (0.4%, N=2); and urinary retention (0.4%, N=2) were the reasons for discontinuation reported by more than 1 patient. Seizures — STRATTERA has not been systematically evaluated in adult patients with a seizure disorder as these patients were excluded from clinical studies during the product's premarket testing. In the clinical development program, seizures were reported on 0.1% (1/748) of adult patients. In these clinical trials, no poor metabolizers (0/43) reported seizures compared to 0.1% (1/705) for extensive metabolizers. Commonly observed adverse reactions in acute adult placebo-controlled trials — Commonly observed adverse reactions associated with the use of STRATTERA (incidence of 2% or greater) and not observed at an equivalent incidence among placebo-treated patients (STRATTERA incidence greater than placebo) are listed in Table 3. The most commonly observed adverse reactions in patients treated with STRATTERA (incidence of 5% or greater and at least twice the incidence in placebo patients) were: constipation, dry mouth, nausea, fatigue, decreased appetite, insomnia, erectile dysfunction, urinary hesitation and/or urinary retention and/or dysuria, dysmenorrhea, and hot flush (see Table 3). Male and female sexual dysfunction — Atomoxetine appears to impair sexual function in some patients. Changes in sexual desire, sexual performance, and sexual satisfaction are not well assessed in most clinical trials because they need special attention and because patients and physicians may be reluctant to discuss them. Accordingly, estimates of the incidence of untoward sexual experience and performance cited in product labeling are likely to underestimate the actual incidence. Table 3 above displays the incidence of sexual side effects reported by at least 2% of adult patients taking STRATTERA in placebo-controlled trials. There are no adequate and well-controlled studies examining sexual dysfunction with STRATTERA treatment. While it is difficult to know the precise risk of sexual dysfunction associated with the use of STRATTERA, physicians should routinely inquire about such possible side effects. 6.2 Postmarketing Spontaneous Reports The following adverse reactions have been identified during post approval use of STRATTERA. Unless otherwise specified, these adverse reactions have occurred in adults and children and adolescents. Because these reactions are reported voluntarily from a population of uncertain size, it is not always possible to reliably estimate their frequency or establish a causal relationship to drug exposure. Cardiovascular system — QT prolongation, syncope. General disorders and administration site conditions — Lethargy. Nervous system disorders — Hypoaesthesia; paraesthesia in children and adolescents; sensory disturbances; tics. Psychiatric disorders — Depression and depressed mood; anxiety. Seizures — Seizures have been reported in the postmarketing period. The postmarketing seizure cases include patients with pre-existing seizure disorders and those with identified risk factors for seizures, as well as patients with neither a history of nor identified risk factors for seizures. The exact relationship between STRATTERA and seizures is difficult to evaluate due to uncertainty about the background risk of seizures in ADHD patients. Skin and subcutaneous tissue disorders — Hyperhidrosis. Urogenital system — Male pelvic pain; urinary hesitation in children and adolescents; urinary retention in children and adolescents. Most common adverse reactions (≥5% and at least twice the incidence of placebo patients) Child and Adolescent Clinical Trials – Nausea, vomiting, fatigue, decreased appetite, abdominal pain, and somnolence. (6.1) Adult Clinical Trials – Constipation, dry mouth, nausea, fatigue, decreased appetite, insomnia, erectile dysfunction, urinary hesitation and/or urinary retention and/or dysuria, dysmenorrhea, and hot flush. (6.1) To report SUSPECTED ADVERSE REACTIONS, contact Eli Lilly and Company at 1-800-LillyRx (1-800-545-5979) or FDA at 1-800-FDA-1088 or www.fda.gov/medwatch"
      ],
      "how_supplied": [
        "Opaque Blue, Opaque White LILLY 3228 25 mg 16.2 Storage and Handling Store at 25°C (77°F); excursions permitted to 15° to 30°C (59° to 86°F) [see USP Controlled Room Temperature]."
      ],
      "information_for_patients": [
        "17 PATIENT COUNSELING INFORMATION See FDA-approved Medication Guide. 17.1 General Information Physicians should instruct their patients to read the Medication Guide before starting therapy with STRATTERA and to reread it each time the prescription is renewed. Prescribers or other health professionals should inform patients, their families, and their caregivers about the benefits and risks associated with treatment with STRATTERA and should counsel them in its appropriate use. The prescriber or health professional should instruct patients, their families, and their caregivers to read the Medication Guide and should assist them in understanding its contents. Patients should be given the opportunity to discuss the contents of the Medication Guide and to obtain answers to any questions they may have. Patients should be advised of the following issues and asked to alert their prescriber if these occur while taking STRATTERA. 17.2 Suicide Risk Patients, their families, and their caregivers should be encouraged to be alert to the emergence of anxiety, agitation, panic attacks, insomnia, irritability, hostility, aggressiveness, impulsivity, akathisia (psychomotor restlessness), hypomania, mania, other unusual changes in behavior, depression, and suicidal ideation, especially early during STRATTERA treatment and when the dose is adjusted. Families and caregivers of patients should be advised to observe for the emergence of such symptoms on a day-to-day basis, since changes may be abrupt. Such symptoms should be reported to the patient's prescriber or health professional, especially if they are severe, abrupt in onset, or were not part of the patient's presenting symptoms. Symptoms such as these may be associated with an increased risk for suicidal thinking and behavior and indicate a need for very close monitoring and possibly changes in the medication. 17.3 Severe Liver Injury Patients initiating STRATTERA should be cautioned that severe liver injury may develop. Patients should be instructed to contact their physician immediately should they develop pruritus, dark urine, jaundice, right upper quadrant tenderness, or unexplained “flu-like” symptoms [see Warnings and Precautions (5.2)]. 17.4 Aggression or Hostility Patients should be instructed to call their doctor as soon as possible should they notice an increase in aggression or hostility. 17.5 Priapism Rare postmarketing cases of priapism, defined as painful and nonpainful penile erection lasting more than 4 hours, have been reported for pediatric and adult patients treated with STRATTERA. The parents or guardians of pediatric patients taking STRATTERA and adult patients taking STRATTERA should be instructed that priapism requires prompt medical attention. 17.6 Ocular Irritant STRATTERA is an ocular irritant. STRATTERA capsules are not intended to be opened. In the event of capsule content coming in contact with the eye, the affected eye should be flushed immediately with water, and medical advice obtained. Hands and any potentially contaminated surfaces should be washed as soon as possible. 17.7 Drug-Drug Interaction Patients should be instructed to consult a physician if they are taking or plan to take any prescription or over-the-counter medicines, dietary supplements, or herbal remedies. 17.8 Pregnancy Patients should be instructed to consult a physician if they are nursing, pregnant, or thinking of becoming pregnant while taking STRATTERA. 17.9 Food Patients may take STRATTERA with or without food. 17.10 Missed Dose If patients miss a dose, they should be instructed to take it as soon as possible, but should not take more than the prescribed total daily amount of STRATTERA in any 24-hour period. 17.11 Interference with Psychomotor Performance Patients should be instructed to use caution when driving a car or operating hazardous machinery until they are reasonably certain that their performance is not affected by atomoxetine. Literature revised July 29, 2010 Eli Lilly and Company Indianapolis, IN 46285, USA www.strattera.com Copyright © 2002, 2010, Eli Lilly and Company. All rights reserved. PV 6265 AMP"
      ],
      "package_label_principal_display_panel": [
        "image of label image of label"
      ],
      "spl_medguide": [
        "STRATTERA - atomoxetine hydrochloride capsule STRATTERA - atomoxetine hydrochloride Eli Lilly and Company ---------- MEDICATION GUIDE STRATTERA ® (Stra-TAIR-a) (atomoxetine hydrochloride) Read the Medication Guide that comes with STRATTERA® before you or your child starts taking it and each time you get a refill. There may be new information. This Medication Guide does not take the place of talking to your doctor about your treatment or your child's treatment with STRATTERA. What is the most important information I should know about STRATTERA? The following have been reported with use of STRATTERA: 1. Suicidal thoughts and actions in children and teenagers: Children and teenagers sometimes think about suicide, and many report trying to kill themselves. Results from STRATTERA clinical studies with over 2200 child or teenage ADHD patients suggest that some children and teenagers may have a higher chance of having suicidal thoughts or actions. Although no suicides occurred in these studies, 4 out of every 1000 patients developed suicidal thoughts. Tell your child or teenager's doctor if your child or teenager (or there is a family history of): has bipolar illness (manic-depressive illness) had suicide thoughts or actions before starting STRATTERA The chance for suicidal thoughts and actions may be higher: early during STRATTERA treatment during dose adjustments Prevent suicidal thoughts and action in your child or teenager by: paying close attention to your child or teenager's moods, behaviors, thoughts, and feelings during STRATTERA treatment keeping all follow-up visits with your child or teenager's doctor as scheduled Watch for the following signs in your child or teenager during STRATTERA treatment: anxiety agitation panic attacks trouble sleeping irritability hostility aggressiveness impulsivity restlessness mania depression suicide thoughts Call your child or teenager's doctor right away if they have any of the above signs, especially if they are new, sudden, or severe. Your child or teenager may need to be closely watched for suicidal thoughts and actions or need a change in medicine. 2. Severe liver damage: STRATTERA can cause liver injury in some patients. Call your doctor right away if you or your child has the following signs of liver problems: itching right upper belly pain dark urine yellow skin or eyes unexplained flu-like symptoms 3. Heart-related problems: sudden death in patients who have heart problems or heart defects stroke and heart attack in adults increased blood pressure and heart rate Tell your doctor if you or your child has any heart problems, heart defects, high blood pressure, or a family history of these problems. Your doctor should check you or your child carefully for heart problems before starting STRATTERA. Your doctor should check your blood pressure or your child's blood pressure and heart rate regularly during treatment with STRATTERA. Call your doctor right away if you or your child has any signs of heart problems such as chest pain, shortness of breath, or fainting while taking STRATTERA. 4. New mental (psychiatric) problems in children and teenagers: new psychotic symptoms (such as hearing voices, believing things that are not true, being suspicious) or new manic symptoms Call your child or teenager's doctor right away about any new mental symptoms because adjusting or stopping STRATTERA treatment may need to be considered. What Is STRATTERA? STRATTERA is a selective norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor medicine. It is used for the treatment of attention deficit and hyperactivity disorder (ADHD). STRATTERA may help increase attention and decrease impulsiveness and hyperactivity in patients with ADHD. STRATTERA should be used as a part of a total treatment program for ADHD that may include counseling or other therapies. STRATTERA has not been studied in children less than 6 years old. Who should not take STRATTERA? STRATTERA should not be taken if you or your child: are taking or have taken within the past 14 days an anti-depression medicine called a monoamine oxidase inhibitor or MAOI. Some names of MAOI medicines are Nardil® (phenelzine sulfate), Parnate® (tranylcypromine sulfate) and Emsam® (selegiline transdermal system). have an eye problem called narrow angle glaucoma are allergic to anything in STRATTERA. See the end of this Medication Guide for a complete list of ingredients. STRATTERA may not be right for you or your child. Before starting STRATTERA tell your doctor or your child's doctor about all health conditions (or a family history of) including: have or had suicide thoughts or actions heart problems, heart defects, irregular heart beat, high blood pressure, or low blood pressure mental problems, psychosis, mania, bipolar illness, or depression liver problems Tell your doctor if you or your child is pregnant, planning to become pregnant, or breastfeeding. Can STRATTERA be taken with other medicines? Tell your doctor about all the medicines that you or your child takes including prescription and nonprescription medicines, vitamins, and herbal supplements. STRATTERA and some medicines may interact with each other and cause serious side effects. Your doctor will decide whether STRATTERA can be taken with other medicines. Especially tell your doctor if you or your child takes: asthma medicines anti-depression medicines including MAOIs blood pressure medicines cold or allergy medicines that contain decongestants Know the medicines that you or your child takes. Keep a list of your medicines with you to show your doctor and pharmacist. Do not start any new medicine while taking STRATTERA without talking to your doctor first. How should STRATTERA be taken? Take STRATTERA exactly as prescribed. STRATTERA comes in different dose strength capsules. Your doctor may adjust the dose until it is right for you or your child. Do not chew, crush, or open the capsules. Swallow STRATTERA capsules whole with water or other liquids. Tell your doctor if you or your child cannot swallow STRATTERA whole. A different medicine may need to be prescribed. Avoid touching a broken STRATTERA capsule. Wash hands and surfaces that touched an open STRATTERA capsule. If any of the powder gets in your eyes or your child's eyes, rinse them with water right away and call your doctor. STRATTERA can be taken with or without food. STRATTERA is usually taken once or twice a day. Take STRATTERA at the same time each day to help you remember. If you miss a dose of STRATTERA, take it as soon as you remember that day. If you miss a day of STRATTERA, do not double your dose the next day. Just skip the day you missed. From time to time, your doctor may stop STRATTERA treatment for a while to check ADHD symptoms. Your doctor may do regular checks of the blood, heart, and blood pressure while taking STRATTERA. Children should have their height and weight checked often while taking STRATTERA. STRATTERA treatment may be stopped if a problem is found during these check-ups. If you or your child takes too much STRATTERA or overdoses, call your doctor or poison control center right away, or get emergency treatment. What are possible side effects of STRATTERA? See “What is the most important information I should know about STRATTERA?” for information on reported suicidal thoughts and actions, other mental problems, severe liver damage, and heart problems. Other serious side effects include: serious allergic reactions (call your doctor if you have trouble breathing, see swelling or hives, or experience other allergic reactions) slowing of growth (height and weight) in children problems passing urine including trouble starting or keeping a urine stream cannot fully empty the bladder Common side effects in children and teenagers include: upset stomach decreased appetite nausea or vomiting dizziness tiredness mood swings Common side effects in adults include: constipation dry mouth nausea decreased appetite dizziness trouble sleeping sexual side effects menstrual cramps problems passing urine Other information for children, teenagers, and adults: Erections that won't go away (priapism) have occurred rarely during treatment with STRATTERA. If you have an erection that lasts more than 4 hours, seek medical help right away. Because of the potential for lasting damage, including the potential inability to have erections, priapism should be evaluated by a doctor immediately. STRATTERA may affect your ability or your child's ability to drive or operate heavy machinery. Be careful until you know how STRATTERA affects you or your child. Talk to your doctor if you or your child has side effects that are bothersome or do not go away. This is not a complete list of possible side effects. Call your doctor for medical advice about side effects. You may report side effects to FDA at 1-800-FDA-1088. How should I store STRATTERA? Store STRATTERA in a safe place at room temperature, 59 to 86°F (15 to 30°C). Keep STRATTERA and all medicines out of the reach of children. General information about STRATTERA Medicines are sometimes prescribed for purposes other than those listed in a Medication Guide. Do not use STRATTERA for a condition for which it was not prescribed. Do not give STRATTERA to other people, even if they have the same condition. It may harm them. This Medication Guide summarizes the most important information about STRATTERA. If you would like more information, talk with your doctor. You can ask your doctor or pharmacist for information about STRATTERA that was written for healthcare professionals. For more information about STRATTERA call 1-800-Lilly-Rx (1-800-545-5979) or visit www.strattera.com. What are the ingredients in STRATTERA? Active ingredient: atomoxetine hydrochloride. Nardil® is a registered trademark of Pfizer Inc. Parnate® is a registered trademark of GlaxoSmithKline. Emsam® is a registered trademark of Somerset Pharmaceuticals Inc. This Medication Guide has been approved by the US Food and Drug Administration. Patient Information revised July 29, 2010 Eli Lilly and Company Indianapolis, IN 46285, USA www.strattera.com Copyright © 2003, 2010, Eli Lilly and Company. All rights reserved. PV 5855 AMP Revised: 08/2010 Eli Lilly and Company"
      ],
      "indications_and_usage": [
        "1 INDICATIONS AND USAGE 1.1 Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) STRATTERA is indicated for the treatment of Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD). The efficacy of STRATTERA Capsules was established in seven clinical trials in outpatients with ADHD: four 6 to 9-week trials in pediatric patients (ages 6 to 18), two 10-week trial in adults, and one maintenance trial in pediatrics (ages 6 to 15) [see Clinical Studies (14)]. 1.2 Diagnostic Considerations A diagnosis of ADHD (DSM-IV) implies the presence of hyperactive-impulsive or inattentive symptoms that cause impairment and that were present before age 7 years. The symptoms must be persistent, must be more severe than is typically observed in individuals at a comparable level of development, must cause clinically significant impairment, e.g., in social, academic, or occupational functioning, and must be present in 2 or more settings, e.g., school (or work) and at home. The symptoms must not be better accounted for by another mental disorder. The specific etiology of ADHD is unknown, and there is no single diagnostic test. Adequate diagnosis requires the use not only of medical but also of special psychological, educational, and social resources. Learning may or may not be impaired. The diagnosis must be based upon a complete history and evaluation of the patient and not solely on the presence of the required number of DSM-IV characteristics. For the Inattentive Type, at least 6 of the following symptoms must have persisted for at least 6 months: lack of attention to details/careless mistakes, lack of sustained attention, poor listener, failure to follow through on tasks, poor organization, avoids tasks requiring sustained mental effort, loses things, easily distracted, forgetful. For the Hyperactive-Impulsive Type, at least 6 of the following symptoms must have persisted for at least 6 months: fidgeting/squirming, leaving seat, inappropriate running/climbing, difficulty with quiet activities, “on the go,” excessive talking, blurting answers, can't wait turn, intrusive. For a Combined Type diagnosis, both inattentive and hyperactive-impulsive criteria must be met. 1.3 Need for Comprehensive Treatment Program STRATTERA is indicated as an integral part of a total treatment program for ADHD that may include other measures (psychological, educational, social) for patients with this syndrome. Drug treatment may not be indicated for all patients with this syndrome. Drug treatment is not intended for use in the patient who exhibits symptoms secondary to environmental factors and/or other primary psychiatric disorders, including psychosis. Appropriate educational placement is essential in children and adolescents with this diagnosis and psychosocial intervention is often helpful. When remedial measures alone are insufficient, the decision to prescribe drug treatment medication will depend upon the physician's assessment of the chronicity and severity of the patient's symptoms. STRATTERA® is a selective norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor indicated for the treatment of Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD). (1.1)"
      ],
      "clinical_pharmacology": [
        "12 CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY 12.1 Mechanism of Action The precise mechanism by which atomoxetine produces its therapeutic effects in Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) is unknown, but is thought to be related to selective inhibition of the pre-synaptic norepinephrine transporter, as determined in ex vivo uptake and neurotransmitter depletion studies. 12.2 Pharmacodynamics An exposure-response analysis encompassing doses of atomoxetine (0.5, 1.2 or 1.8 mg/kg/day) or placebo demonstrated atomoxetine exposure correlates with efficacy as measured by the Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder Rating Scale-IV-Parent Version: Investigator administered and scored. The exposure-efficacy relationship was similar to that observed between dose and efficacy with median exposures at the two highest doses resulting in near maximal changes from baseline [see Clinical Studies (14.2)]. 12.3 Pharmacokinetics Atomoxetine is well-absorbed after oral administration and is minimally affected by food. It is eliminated primarily by oxidative metabolism through the cytochrome P450 2D6 (CYP2D6) enzymatic pathway and subsequent glucuronidation. Atomoxetine has a half-life of about 5 hours. A fraction of the population (about 7% of Caucasians and 2% of African Americans) are poor metabolizers (PMs) of CYP2D6 metabolized drugs. These individuals have reduced activity in this pathway resulting in 10-fold higher AUCs, 5-fold higher peak plasma concentrations, and slower elimination (plasma half-life of about 24 hours) of atomoxetine compared with people with normal activity [extensive metabolizers (EMs)]. Drugs that inhibit CYP2D6, such as fluoxetine, paroxetine, and quinidine, cause similar increases in exposure. The pharmacokinetics of atomoxetine have been evaluated in more than 400 children and adolescents in selected clinical trials, primarily using population pharmacokinetic studies. Single-dose and steady-state individual pharmacokinetic data were also obtained in children, adolescents, and adults. When doses were normalized to a mg/kg basis, similar half-life, Cmax, and AUC values were observed in children, adolescents, and adults. Clearance and volume of distribution after adjustment for body weight were also similar. Absorption and distribution — Atomoxetine is rapidly absorbed after oral administration, with absolute bioavailability of about 63% in EMs and 94% in PMs. Maximal plasma concentrations (Cmax) are reached approximately 1 to 2 hours after dosing. STRATTERA can be administered with or without food. Administration of STRATTERA with a standard high-fat meal in adults did not affect the extent of oral absorption of atomoxetine (AUC), but did decrease the rate of absorption, resulting in a 37% lower Cmax, and delayed Tmax by 3 hours. In clinical trials with children and adolescents, administration of STRATTERA with food resulted in a 9% lower Cmax. The steady-state volume of distribution after intravenous administration is 0.85 L/kg indicating that atomoxetine distributes primarily into total body water. Volume of distribution is similar across the patient weight range after normalizing for body weight. At therapeutic concentrations, 98% of atomoxetine in plasma is bound to protein, primarily albumin. Metabolism and elimination — Atomoxetine is metabolized primarily through the CYP2D6 enzymatic pathway. People with reduced activity in this pathway (PMs) have higher plasma concentrations of atomoxetine compared with people with normal activity (EMs). For PMs, AUC of atomoxetine is approximately 10-fold and Css,max is about 5-fold greater than EMs. Laboratory tests are available to identify CYP2D6 PMs. Coadministration of STRATTERA with potent inhibitors of CYP2D6, such as fluoxetine, paroxetine, or quinidine, results in a substantial increase in atomoxetine plasma exposure, and dosing adjustment may be necessary [see Warnings and Precautions (5.13)]. Atomoxetine did not inhibit or induce the CYP2D6 pathway. The major oxidative metabolite formed, regardless of CYP2D6 status, is 4-hydroxyatomoxetine, which is glucuronidated. 4-Hydroxyatomoxetine is equipotent to atomoxetine as an inhibitor of the norepinephrine transporter but circulates in plasma at much lower concentrations (1% of atomoxetine concentration in EMs and 0.1% of atomoxetine concentration in PMs). 4-Hydroxyatomoxetine is primarily formed by CYP2D6, but in PMs, 4-hydroxyatomoxetine is formed at a slower rate by several other cytochrome P450 enzymes. N-Desmethylatomoxetine is formed by CYP2C19 and other cytochrome P450 enzymes, but has substantially less pharmacological activity compared with atomoxetine and circulates in plasma at lower concentrations (5% of atomoxetine concentration in EMs and 45% of atomoxetine concentration in PMs). Mean apparent plasma clearance of atomoxetine after oral administration in adult EMs is 0.35 L/hr/kg and the mean half-life is 5.2 hours. Following oral administration of atomoxetine to PMs, mean apparent plasma clearance is 0.03 L/hr/kg and mean half-life is 21.6 hours. For PMs, AUC of atomoxetine is approximately 10-fold and Css,max is about 5-fold greater than EMs. The elimination half-life of 4-hydroxyatomoxetine is similar to that of N-desmethylatomoxetine (6 to 8 hours) in EM subjects, while the half-life of N-desmethylatomoxetine is much longer in PM subjects (34 to 40 hours). Atomoxetine is excreted primarily as 4-hydroxyatomoxetine-O-glucuronide, mainly in the urine (greater than 80% of the dose) and to a lesser extent in the feces (less than 17% of the dose). Only a small fraction of the STRATTERA dose is excreted as unchanged atomoxetine (less than 3% of the dose), indicating extensive biotransformation. [See Use In Specific Populations (8.4, 8.5, 8.6, 8.7, 8.8, 8.9)]."
      ],
      "set_id": "0121363e-dcd9-4c24-940b-ea890ab762e7",
      "id": "5f48f6d9-92c0-4437-b354-5cbe1ac225cf",
      "overdosage": [
        "10 OVERDOSAGE 10.1 Human Experience No fatal overdoses occurred in clinical trials. There is limited clinical trial experience with STRATTERA overdose. During postmarketing, there have been fatalities reported involving a mixed ingestion overdose of STRATTERA and at least one other drug. There have been no reports of death involving overdose of STRATTERA alone, including intentional overdoses at amounts up to 1400 mg. In some cases of overdose involving STRATTERA, seizures have been reported. The most commonly reported symptoms accompanying acute and chronic overdoses of STRATTERA were somnolence, agitation, hyperactivity, abnormal behavior, and gastrointestinal symptoms. Signs and symptoms consistent with mild to moderate sympathetic nervous system activation (e.g., mydriasis, tachycardia, dry mouth) have also been observed. Less commonly, there have been reports of QT prolongation and mental changes, including disorientation and hallucinations. 10.2 Management of Overdose An airway should be established. Monitoring of cardiac and vital signs is recommended, along with appropriate symptomatic and supportive measures. Gastric lavage may be indicated if performed soon after ingestion. Activated charcoal may be useful in limiting absorption. Because atomoxetine is highly protein-bound, dialysis is not likely to be useful in the treatment of overdose."
      ]
    }
  ]
}